Su Zhang

Software Engineer

CONTACT ME

1 0451 991 558

suzhang79@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/su-zhang-au

https://github.com/coderGirlSu

https://codergirlsu.dev/

Sydney

EDUCATION

Diploma of Information Technology

Coder Academy 2022

Bachelor of Architecture

Harbin Institute of Technology 2010 - 2013

Environmental Art Design

Harbin Institute of Technology 2006 - 2009

STRENGTHS

- Full Stack Web App Development
- · Backend Development
- Self Learning
- Problem solving
- AWS fundamental services
- Fluent in Mandarin

SKILLS

- Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Golang, Ruby, Python, Node.js, HTML, CSS.
- Frameworks: React, Ruby on Rails ,gRPC, Rest, Jest
- Software: VSCode, Figma, SourceTree, AutoCAD, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Tools: Buildkite, Backstage, Kubernetes, Git, GitHub, Trello, Heroku, Firebase, Agile Board, Postman, XMind, Balsamiq, draw.io

SUMMARY

I'm a junior full-stack Software Engineer specialising in modern technologies such as React, TypeScript, Node.js, gRPC, Golang, and Temporal. With experience working on advanced projects involving the Boston Dynamics Spot Robot, I have developed an understanding of robotics, autonomous navigation, and data collection. My design thinking and problem-solving skills originally honed through a background in Buildings Architecture, now allow me to apply these technologies with a fresh perspective to solve complex problems in IT.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full stack Software Engineer

SafetyCulture Intern

2022-2023

- Implemented a Data governance workflow feature end-to-end using Figma, React, TypeScript, gRPC, Golang, and Temporal.
- Developed a solution using a Boston Dynamics' Spot robot to autonomously navigate and collect IR temperature data using Python.
- Delivered comprehensive presentations of my work to an engineering department of 150+ engineers.
- Collaborated across multiple engineering teams to implement a comprehensive solution for managing sensitive customer data in AWS, ensuring full compliance with data governance requests.

Graphic designer

Access Displays & Digital Printing Pty Ltd

2019-2021

- Communicated with clients and consumers to develop designs to requirements
- Collaborated with other designers and printing companies to create highquality products and websites

Buildings Architect

2011-2018

Architectural Design and Research Institute of Harbin University of Science and Technology

- Created and designed drawings that met client requirements and conformed to design specifications
- Communicated with clients to determine planning project requirements and provided updates accordingly
- Coordinated the design team to ensure aspects such as structural support, water, and electricity arrangements were coordinated throughout the project

ACHIEVEMENTS

AWS Cloud Practitioner Certificate

2023

Credentials:

https://www.credly.com/badges/4519b7fc-ecbe-419c-8d2c-948bd3cafd34/public_url

- Successfully obtained the AWS Cloud Practitioner certification in 2023, demonstrating a strong foundation in cloud computing principles and AWS services
- Proficient in core AWS cloud concepts, including cloud architecture, security, and billing, along with a deep understanding of fundamental AWS services and their use cases
- Skilled in managing AWS cloud infrastructure, including virtual servers (EC2), storage (S3), and databases (RDS), ensuring optimal performance and costefficiency
- Well-versed in cloud best practices, enabling the design and implementation of scalable, reliable, and secure AWS solutions that meet business objectives and compliance requirements.

KEY PROJECTS

Hackathon - Boston Dynamics Spot

- Created an innovative solution during the Boston Dynamics Spot Hackathon at SafetyCulture that involved programming Spot to independently navigate a predetermined path, capture high-quality photos, and measure temperature using an infrared sensor.
- Utilised the data collected by Spot to conduct a comprehensive inspection through the SafetyCulture app that provided valuable insights into safety and maintenance requirements, thereby automating tasks that were previously time-consuming, dangerous, and error-prone.
- Leveraged API development skills to successfully upload all media to an inspection device that SafetyCulture customers can use for more efficient and accurate inspections, enabling seamless access to valuable findings.

Temporal - data governance workflow

- Implemented a Data Governance feature utilising advanced technologies such as Figma, React, TypeScript, gRPC, Go, and Temporal Workflow.
- · Developed an intuitive and user-friendly interface for managing data using Figma, React, and TypeScript.
- Utilised gRPC and Go to create a fast and reliable backend for the feature.
- Integrated Temporal Workflow to efficiently manage complex workflows and ensure the smooth running of the feature.
- Presented the Data Governance feature to a large audience of over 150 engineers within the engineering department.
- Demonstrated exceptional technical expertise and dedication in the successful implementation of the feature.

MERN stack - Chat App

- Spearheaded the development of a feature-rich MERN stack chat application in collaboration with a team of two.
- Incorporated advanced features such as user authentication, group creation and chat rooms, chat history viewing, adding friends, dark mode, and custom Halloween theme to provide an enhanced user experience.
- Employed Express for advanced backend features and deployed the application on AWS EC2 instances.
- · Leveraged Firebase authentication and MongoDB Atlas for efficient database management.
- Utilised React for front-end development and deployed on Netlify for ease of use.
- Ensured the chat software has scalability and provides a solid foundation for future feature development.

Hackathon - React Emoji Search App

- Built an app to search emojis in a four-person team in one and a half days
- · Used ReactJS, JavaScript, CSS and HTML including a YouTube presentation and documentation
- Includes features such as search, click-to-copy emoji, pop-up toast notifications, dark mode and team photos
- · Collaboration with team using GitHub fork workflow and PRs
- · Deployed on Netlify
- App website: https://emojis.codergirlsu.dev/
- YouTube presentation: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tTJmHIxH-fo
- GitHub: https://github.com/coderGirlSu/coder-academy-hackathon-team-why-not

Ruby on Rails - Marketplace

- Created a two-sided marketplace with the following features:
 - File upload capabilities, user authentication, messaging, search, sorting and filtering capabilities
- · Developed using Ruby on Rails, and PostgreSQL, and deployed to Heroku
- Github: https://github.com/coderGirlSu/SuZhang_T2A2

Portfolio website

- Created a portfolio website to provide information about me, my skills, interests, and professional knowledge and a showcase of
 my work
- · Developed using HTML and CSS
- App website: https://codergirlsu.github.io/src/

VOLUNTEERING

Australian Red Cross

• Sale of new and donated clothes, accessories and household items to raise funds to help those in need. Categorised donations and organised products for sale. Provide customer service and process sales